<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>transition &#8211; Sorry for the Spam</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/transition/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The Adventures of Dan Schultz</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 21:10:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Media Labs and Open News</title>
		<link>/2012/06/media-labs-and-open-news/</link>
					<comments>/2012/06/media-labs-and-open-news/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 21:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenNews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With my thesis complete I&#8217;m about to embark on the next phase in life, and in true Millennial fashion it will last about 10 months because job security is for chumps. I&#8217;m going to be a Knight-Mozilla Fellow (feel free to call me &#8220;Mr. Fellow&#8221;) working in The Boston Globe as part of the Open [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With my thesis complete I&#8217;m about to embark on the next phase in life, and in true Millennial fashion it will last about 10 months because job security is for chumps.  I&#8217;m going to be a Knight-Mozilla Fellow (feel free to call me &#8220;Mr. Fellow&#8221;) working in <a href="http://bostonglobe.com/">The Boston Globe</a> as part of the <a href="http://opennews.org/">Open News</a> project led by the <a href="http://www.knightfoundation.org/">Knight Foundation</a> and the <a href="http://www.mozillafoundation.org/">Mozilla Foundation</a>.</p>
<p>My first full day was yesterday and I&#8217;m just about finished a post about my first impressions and lessons learned.  Before I hit publish on that, though, I want to give a nod to the option I decided <em>not</em> to pursue: a PhD at the MIT Media Lab.</p>
<h2>Choosing a Path</h2>
<p>I ultimately decided not to apply to the PhD program at the Media Lab for now.  This wasn&#8217;t easy (and doesn&#8217;t mean I won&#8217;t come back and apply later), but it came down to a few points:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/yunodoctorate-e1338930095522.jpg" alt="" title="yunodoctorate" width="280" height="280" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-803" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/yunodoctorate-e1338930095522.jpg 280w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/yunodoctorate-e1338930095522-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/06/yunodoctorate-e1338930095522-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 280px) 100vw, 280px" /></p>
<p><strong>I&#8217;m not really a great academic.</strong>  Don&#8217;t get me wrong, the motto of &#8220;Demo or Die&#8221; generally trumps &#8220;Publish or Perish&#8221; at the Media Lab, but this doesn&#8217;t change the fact that a PhD is ultimately an academic endeavor.  When it comes to technology my natural inclination is to code and blog, not to design studies and write scientific papers.</p>
<p><strong>I got a huge amount out of my time at the lab.</strong> Yes, the awesome ability of the Media Lab to jump start lives is actually part of why I&#8217;m moving on.  In two years I feel empowered to create anything I want, I&#8217;ve redefined my understanding of the world, quadrupled my confidence, developed an amazing network of friends and connections, and  become part of a wonderful community.  I&#8217;m sure that four more years at the lab would continue improvement on all of those fronts, but I doubt that it would be nearly as saturated.</p>
<p><strong>Four years is much longer than 10 months.</strong> Call me an opportunist but I&#8217;m married, and who knows where Lyla and I will want to be over the next four years.  Actually it turns out we do know (Lyla got into RISD and starts her graduate program in September), but that isn&#8217;t the point.  Locking myself into something for four years seems dangerous at a time when there are so many problems to solve and ideas to pursue.  What would have happened if Luke just chilled out with Yoda for four years?</p>
<p>All of that being said, if I ever commit to a PhD it will be at the Media Lab.  I already miss the place!  Luckily I&#8217;ll stay an official part of it for at least another year as a &#8220;zero cost visiting researcher.&#8221;  This means I don&#8217;t get paid, but I get to keep access to resources and have a good explanation as to why I&#8217;m still skulking around the hallways at night.</p>
<p>This leaves me here, living the Tolkien dream and beginning a brand new fellowship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2012/06/media-labs-and-open-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joining the Starship Eco</title>
		<link>/2010/09/joining-the-starship-eco/</link>
					<comments>/2010/09/joining-the-starship-eco/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information Ecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT Media Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Classes didn&#8217;t start until Wednesday, but as I learned during orientation we are not just students &#8212; we&#8217;re also employees working under our advisers.  My boss/adviser, Henry Holtzman, heads the &#8220;Information Ecology&#8221; group, which focuses on making information more naturally accessible in the physical world.  I highly suggest you check out the group website and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Classes didn&#8217;t start until Wednesday, but as I learned during orientation we are not just students &#8212; we&#8217;re also employees working under our advisers.  My boss/adviser, Henry Holtzman, heads the &#8220;Information Ecology&#8221; group, which focuses on making information more naturally accessible in the physical world.  I highly suggest you check out <a href="http://eco.media.mit.edu/">the group website</a> and look at their projects.  Some highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Proverbial Wallet</strong> &#8212; a wallet that is linked into your bank accounts via bluetooth and your cell phone, and which becomes more difficult to open when you have a high credit card balance.  The idea is that this naturally allows you to get a sense of your digital finances without having to check online.</li>
<li><strong>The BiDi Screen</strong> &#8212; this is a monitor that not only displays photons, but also collects them.  In other words, each pixel is also a camera, which means the computer can take low resolution 3d images.  Using this technology computers can easily detect gestures in front of it.  (Check out <a href="http://vimeo.com/8111549">this video</a>)</li>
<li><strong>The Home Fabratory</strong> &#8212; this is basically a $100 &#8220;fabrication&#8221; set.  Fabrication is the act of creating something in physical space; so, for instance, a sculpture, or a circuit board.  This thing is one step closer towards making it so people can start building stuff in their own homes without having to spend a fortune.  The ultimate goal is the Star Trek replicator!  (<a href="http://makeyourbot.org/">the project&#8217;s web site</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>There are dozens of other projects, but I&#8217;ll let you guys check them out if you want to since they are all listed and described on the group website.</p>
<p>On Tuesday morning I took the &#8220;T&#8221; (the Boston subway system) down to The Media Lab.  The lab itself is actually two buildings: the new one (which was  first opened this past summer), and the &#8220;classic&#8221; one.  The new building  is pretty much made of glass, which means all the walls are transparent and you can look into the lab space from outside.  The main rooms  are very large and host about 4 research groups.  Our group happens to be located next to a glass wall on the 3rd floor that overlooks the lobby!</p>
<p>My first day was pretty low key, and it mostly involved meeting the other group members and cleaning up / reorganizing our lab space.  We came up with a really great design, which we call &#8220;the armada.&#8221; It&#8217;s a giant semi circle of desks that overlooks the rest of the &#8220;New&#8221; Media Lab.  It also creates a corridor to Henry&#8217;s office which means that anyone who wants to visit Henry has to walk in front of the entire armada.  Oh, and it also feels like the bridge of the Starship Enterprise.  We plan on setting up a heads up display against the glass to simulate battles with Klingon warships.</p>
<div id="attachment_895" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-006.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-895" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-006.jpg" alt="The Eco Armada" title="MIT-006" width="400" height="300" class="size-full wp-image-895" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-006.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-006-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-895" class="wp-caption-text">An inside view of the armada (my desk is the far right)</p></div>
<div id="attachment_897" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-047.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-897" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-047.jpg" alt="" title="MIT-047" width="500" height="375" class="size-full wp-image-897" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-047.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-047-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-897" class="wp-caption-text">An outside view of the armada (we&#039;re in the middle -- my desk is the far left computer)</p></div>
<p>I want to end with a message that I found on the walls of one of the offices in my lab space:</p>
<div id="attachment_898" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-898" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT.jpg" alt="A computer without Cobol and Fortran is like a piece of chocolate cake without ketchup and mustard." title="MIT" width="400" height="168" class="size-full wp-image-898" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/MIT-300x126.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-898" class="wp-caption-text">A computer without Cobol and Fortran is like a piece of chocolate cake without ketchup and mustard.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/09/joining-the-starship-eco/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The First 24 Hours of Boston</title>
		<link>/2010/09/the-first-24-hours-of-boston/</link>
					<comments>/2010/09/the-first-24-hours-of-boston/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lyla and I got home from the honeymoon on August 31st at 11:00 PM.  The next day was going to be intense: the plan was to finish packing the entire apartment into boxes, move those boxes into a Uhaul by 3:00, take the 6-hour drive to Boston, and unpack the truck into our new place [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lyla and I got home from the honeymoon on August 31st at 11:00 PM.  The next day was going to be <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MX0D4oZwCsA">intense</a>: the plan was to finish packing the entire apartment into boxes, move those boxes into a Uhaul by 3:00, take the 6-hour drive to Boston, and unpack the truck into our new place in Somerville before it got too late so that I could wake up on time for my orientation the next morning.  Did I mention it was <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=moka3K1o5sY">intense</a>?</p>
<p>Packing was time consuming, but with the help of parents, Erek, Lyla, and I were able to hit the road on schedule&#8230; at 7:30!  Ok not on schedule, but at least we did it.</p>
<div id="attachment_888" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-888" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move.jpg" alt="The UHaul" title="The Move" width="400" height="300" class="size-full wp-image-888" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-888" class="wp-caption-text">This is what the 14 foot Uhaul looked like about an hour before we completely finished.  Mr. Alper was the master behind it all!</p></div>
<p>We almost rushed out before cleaning up but thank goodness my dad was there to step up and vacuum.</p>
<div id="attachment_889" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-889" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move-2.jpg" alt="Dad and a vacuum" title="The-Move-2" width="400" height="300" class="size-full wp-image-889" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move-2.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/The-Move-2-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-889" class="wp-caption-text">Visible proof that there was a vacuum involved!  If only the previous tenants to our new apartment had a dad there to help clean up...</p></div>
<p>The drive itself was all sorts of fun &#8212; I tried to drive the Uhaul on the lower level of the George Washington bridge, which is exactly what you aren&#8217;t allowed to do.  Luckily they account for that sort of thing and we were able to get where we belonged before losing our roof.  Other than that and a few instances of getting lost, we got to the apartment just fine at around 1:30 in the morning.  Who needs to be well rested for their first day of work anyway?</p>
<p>The new apartment was very dirty, which was a bummer, and the walls still had nails and holes kindly left by the previous tenants (the landlord will be repainting them for us soon).  That was the bad news.  The good news was that they left us a refrigerator with two giant bottles of cheap champagne (fun fact: mimosas taste the same no matter how bad the champagne is).  It was a pretty classic scene by the time we finished putting what little we had in there&#8230;</p>
<div id="attachment_891" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-891" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-3.jpg" alt="" title="Move-3" width="400" height="300" class="size-full wp-image-891" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-3.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-3-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-891" class="wp-caption-text">Contents: 13 bottles of beer, 3 liters of champagne, 1 bottle of wine, 2 nalgine bottles (water), peanut butter, jelly, 1/2 a bottle of limoncello, 1/2 a container of orange juice, 1/2 a bottle of flat root beer.  The root beer was the first to go.</p></div>
<p>The next day was orientation, which I was far more nervous about than I needed to be considering the fact that all I had to do was sit there with the 33 other first years.  At orientation I got my first assignment at MIT, and I&#8217;m proud to say that I managed to incorporate StarCraft II into it.</p>
<p>We had to write on the board something that we would be willing to teach &#8212; the idea being that each person would pick something to learn, causing us to naturally get to know a fellow first year student.  I was originally going to teach someone how to play <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uJg8U0QMXEQ">Hysteria</a> on the bass guitar, but unfortunately &#8220;teaching someone to play a song on an instrument&#8221; was used as an example of the type of thing they had in mind, which meant that EVERYONE avoided that lest they appear completely unoriginal.  Instead I offered to teach basic tactics and strategy in SC2 (I should have done the bass thing&#8230; whoops ;)).</p>
<p>When I got home I found that the entire van had already been unpacked by Lyla, Erek, and my dad.  They were supposed to wait so I could help!  After a lot of work, we managed to get the place to the point where Erek and I could set up our computers.</p>
<div id="attachment_892" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-892" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-4.jpg" alt="" title="Move-4" width="400" height="300" class="size-full wp-image-892" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-4.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Move-4-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-892" class="wp-caption-text">Yep, I think we&#039;re all set here (notice how both computer chairs are sliding towards the middle of the room.  That&#039;s because the house is slanted). (Also note the orange wall.)</p></div>
<p>This has nothing to do with the move, but I think &#8220;Uninterested Squirrel&#8221; would be a great name for a band.</p>
<div id="attachment_893" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Uninterested-Squirrel.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-893" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Uninterested-Squirrel.jpg" alt="" title="Uninterested-Squirrel" width="600" height="173" class="size-full wp-image-893" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Uninterested-Squirrel.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Uninterested-Squirrel-300x87.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-893" class="wp-caption-text">She was determined to catch a squirrel in Boston commons.  We lost interest too.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/09/the-first-24-hours-of-boston/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My last day was Friday</title>
		<link>/2010/07/so-i-quit-my-job-on-friday/</link>
					<comments>/2010/07/so-i-quit-my-job-on-friday/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 05:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ColorQuick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had been working for a small web to print company called ColorQuick since June of 2009 to keep me from becoming a homeless person while I waited for Lyla to finish her five-year-long art degree.  Apparently it isn&#8217;t possible to graduate on time if you are a student at Tyler. The experience was worthwhile, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had been working for a small web to print company called <a href="http://www.colorquick.com/">ColorQuick</a> since June of 2009 to keep me from becoming a homeless person while I waited for Lyla to finish her five-year-long art degree.  Apparently it isn&#8217;t possible to graduate on time if you are a student at <a href="http://www.temple.edu/tyler/">Tyler</a>.</p>
<p>The experience was worthwhile, and I learned a lot of good habits along with plenty of things I will forever know to avoid.  The most important takeaway is the value of good project management.  This doesn&#8217;t even have to do with following a particular development methodology &#8212; I am simply talking about having someone who is in charge of fostering and championing a clear vision of the product.  Someone with the time to keep the team organized and moving in the right direction.</p>
<p>Now that I&#8217;m out, though, I&#8217;m doing my best to hit the scalding hot summer ground running.  Between today and September I will be:</p>
<ol>
<li>Working for a truly great startup called <a href="http://www.speakertext.com/">SpeakerText</a>.  They provide interactive transcripts for online videos and I&#8217;m working on the transcript player.</li>
<li>Teaching a few friends how to create web applications (i.e. the art of <a href="http://www.php.net/">PHP</a>, <a href="http://mysql.org/">MySQL</a>,  and <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a>), and working with them on a long-term pet project known to those that know me as <a href="http://thegpf.com/">The GPF</a> (The Globally Personalized Forum).  It&#8217;s going to be a system for group-based-yet-still-personalized communication.</li>
<li>Watching the entire series of Battlestar Galactica for the first time.</li>
<li>Planning a wedding, spending time with my fiance before  she has  to  leave for Spain, and finding an apartment in Cambridge before I have to move there for MIT.  You know, those little things.</li>
</ol>
<p>Since it is 2:00 in the morning, I&#8217;ll abruptly end this ice breaker post with a comment:  If you have ever used Craig&#8217;s list to find apartments and said to yourself &#8220;damn it, I wish I could just see these things on a fracking map&#8221; then rejoice for <a href="http://padmapper.com/">Padmapper.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/07/so-i-quit-my-job-on-friday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (SSL caching disabled) 
Minified using disk
Database Caching using disk

Served from: slifty.com @ 2021-05-25 23:13:20 by W3 Total Cache
-->