<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SpeakerText &#8211; Sorry for the Spam</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/speakertext-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The Adventures of Dan Schultz</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 20:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Quick Overview of Life After Graduating</title>
		<link>/2010/09/a-quick-overview-of-life-after-graduating/</link>
					<comments>/2010/09/a-quick-overview-of-life-after-graduating/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 20:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ColorQuick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpeakerText]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t have any clue who will be reading this blog down the line, but right now I can be pretty sure that it is people I know.Â  To those people &#8211; hello!Â  Sorry this is so impersonal but I&#8217;m really glad to be able to tell you about what I am expecting to be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t have any clue who will be reading this blog down the line, but right now I can be pretty sure that it is people I know.Â  To those people &#8211; hello!Â  Sorry this is so impersonal but I&#8217;m really glad to be able to tell you about what I am expecting to be a really exciting two years.Â  First, though, I want to catch you all up on what has been happening in the somewhat recent past.Â  I know I owe you all a lot of explanation since I stopped sharing tomes of stories three or four years ago, but I think all that is lost to the wind at this point&#8230; whoops!</p>
<p>Anyway, here goes:</p>
<ul>
<li>May 2009 &#8212; I graduated from Carnegie Mellon with a BS in Information Systems and minors in Math and Computer Science.</li>
<li>Fall of 2009 &#8212; I applied to the news challenge with my friend Erek Alper.Â  We made it to the top 50 (out of about 2200).Â  If we had won we would have been given $300k to create a system that routes questions from citizens to the appropriate government representatives and run a pilot in Cheltenham and Pittsburgh.Â  Close but no cigar!</li>
<li>2009 to 2010 &#8212; I worked for ColorQuick (http://www.colorquick.com)/ while Lyla was finishing her fifth year at Tyler / Temple and had lots of productive fun in the real world.</li>
<li>Summer 2010 &#8212; I spent working for a new startup called SpeakerText,  where I worked on an interactive transcript tool that people can use to  add text to their online videos (http://www.speakertext.com)/</li>
<li>March 30th, 2010 &#8212; I was informed by Linda Peterson that I was accepted in to the MIT Media Lab graduate program in Media Arts and Sciences for the Fall of 2010.</li>
<li>July 3, 2010 &#8212; I started this blog, which I will begin to update now that its intended purpose is about to start.</li>
<li>July 27th, 2010 &#8212; Starcraft 2 was released.  (http://www.starcraft2.com).Â / This began two weeks of getting absolutely  nothing done.Â  Then I had to get married so that ruined all my fun!</li>
<li>August 21st, 2010 &#8212; I married Lyla Duey in the Abington Art Center.</li>
<li>August 22nd to August 31st &#8212; we spent nine days in the Gallery Inn, (Old San Juan, Puerto Rico).Â  It was a glorious, relaxing time.</li>
<li>September 1st &#8212; Lyla, Erek, my dad, and I pack up an entire apartment and drive it to Boston.</li>
<li>September 4th &#8212; Lyla moves to Spain for a 10 month program as a Fulbright Scholar.Â  Very exciting!Â  (but, of course, very sad <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f641.png" alt="ðŸ™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> )</li>
</ul>
<p>I think more happened, but this is good enough for now.Â  There, now nobody can say I didn&#8217;t provide basic context for these posts.</p>
<p>Here is a picture of the honeymoon for those that like mushey stuff:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Honeymoon.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124" title="Honeymoon" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/Honeymoon.jpg" alt="" width="327" height="245" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/09/a-quick-overview-of-life-after-graduating/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visiting the SpeakerCave</title>
		<link>/2010/07/visiting-the-speakercave/</link>
					<comments>/2010/07/visiting-the-speakercave/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 18:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpeakerText]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bananas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just got back from an epic journey to a place so manly that Hercules himself would probably be impressed.Â  I visited team SpeakerText! SpeakerText is a true blue startup that I joined a few months ago.Â  We create interactive transcripts for online video which, in addition to providing some pretty great functionality for media [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just got back from an epic journey to a place so manly that Hercules himself would probably be impressed.Â  I visited team SpeakerText!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.speakertext.com/" target="_blank">SpeakerText</a> is a true blue startup that I joined a few months ago.Â  We create <a href="http://thegpf.com:8080/speakertext/Player/">interactive transcripts for online video</a> which, in addition to providing some pretty great functionality for media consumers, also makes it possible for publishers to get their video content cataloged in search engines (&#8220;Video SEO on Steroids&#8221;).</p>
<p>The visit was awesome &#8211; the team is made up of three guys living in an un-air-conditioned 2 bedroom Pittsburgh apartment plus some people like me who visit whenever they get a chance.Â  At the cave, shirts are worn less often than pants and it is common practice to remove clothing before meeting new people.Â  Even before visiting I had already picked up some nice new habits &#8212; <a href="http://www.yammer.com/" target="_blank">yammer</a> being the most fun of them &#8212; but actually living there really pushed the envelope.</p>
<p>Here are just a few of the things I learned:</p>
<ul>
<li>How to use a Mac for dev work (i.e. how awesome <a href="http://macromates.com/" target="_blank">TextMate</a> is)</li>
<li>How to send bananas (i.e. how to use <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git_%28software%29" target="_blank">git</a>)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CHVhwcOg6y8" target="_blank">Bieba time</a>.</li>
<li>Why <a href="http://atomicgator.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/jacob-black-team-jacob-6370903-320-480.jpg" target="_blank">Jacob</a> is Better than <a href="http://corvo-music.com/journal/wp-content/uploads/team-edward-poster.jpg" target="_blank">Edward</a>.</li>
<li>That saying someone is a &#8220;smooth talker&#8221; doesn&#8217;t mean they are a charismatic and intelligent individual.Â  Apparently it implies that he will do something like try to steal your wallet.</li>
<li>I get more awkward than usual around <a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~biglou/" target="_blank">MacArthur Genius Grant recipients</a>.</li>
<li>Good startups build strong friendships.</li>
</ul>
<p>Some of the things on this list make it seem like SpeakerText is actually made up of a bunch of 14 year old girls, and I guess that&#8217;s entirely possible.Â  Nevertheless it was an amazing time and the visit made me realize that it is possible to work on a team without feeling like you are working for someone else.Â  It also forced me to really and truly think about whether or not MIT is what I want to do for the next two years.</p>
<p>While trying to convince me to ditch MIT, team ST asked some really important questions (what do I want to get out of grad school, what do I want to do with my life, etc.) which honestly I hadn&#8217;t fully thought through before.Â  I got there thinking that it wasn&#8217;t even a decision, but by the end I was able to treat it like one.Â  This was the first time I have faced two completely different paths both of which I could take, embrace, and love.</p>
<p>The entire thought process deserves it&#8217;s own post, but I can share the conclusion here: despite the greatness of the team and ideas behind SpeakerText I remain steadfast in my current plans.Â  That being said, I know that I&#8217;m going to be missing out on some once-in-a-lifetime stories and experiences by staying on the east coast while they drive to the other side of the country in a UHaul at the end of the month.</p>
<p>Also. We watched Twilight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/07/visiting-the-speakercave/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (SSL caching disabled) 
Minified using disk
Database Caching using disk

Served from: slifty.com @ 2021-05-25 23:13:25 by W3 Total Cache
-->